

# PARESH MESTRI

Technology Team Lead (<a href="https://learnwithparesh.in">https://learnwithparesh.in</a>)

### **CONTACT**

**Current Address -** "Fulwanti", Kawade Nagar, New Sangavi, Pune – 27

**Permanent Address –** 3290, Murugwada, Ratnagiri - 415612

## Linkedin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/paresh-mestri-875b75107/

#### Github

https://learnwithparesh.github.io/

**PHONE:** 9604435639

#### **EMAIL:**

Paresh.mestri@yahoo.com

- 1	ō

Director

Ratnagiri

Dear Sir,

Greetings of the day!

As a quick introduction, I'M Team Lead, Bachelor's Degree holder in Computer Science; Developer with web development & object oriented analysis design experience in Linux, UNIX, Windows, MS-DOS environment.

I feel confident that I can make substantial contribution towards organization success using my experience and knowledge: Thanks to all me seniors for guidance and opportunity.

Awaiting for positive response,

Paresh Mestri

Pune.

#### **ABOUT ME**

I'M Paresh Sudhakar Mestri.

Team Lead, Bachelor's Degree holder in Computer Science; Developer with web development & object oriented analysis design experience in Linux, UNIX, Windows, MS-DOS environment.

Full life cycle experience, involved in requirement analysis, design, development, testing, deployment and support. Proven success in meeting high level functional requirements and delivering on time. Excellent programming skills and over 4.3 years of experience with JAVA, J2EE, Spring, Hibernate, Struts 2, Ant, ASP.NET, C#, JDBC, C++, OCR Technologies, SQL, Angular, Bootstrap, APIs (developing and connecting to them - RESTful and SOAP), RDBMS and server side software. Sound experience in developing and deploying applications that run on JBoss, tomcat, Apache Web Server, IIS.

Excellent interpersonal skills and Technical skills.

#### Education

2015	Gogate Joglekar College (University Of Mumbai) <b>Bachelor Of Computer Science</b>
2012	Gogate Joglekar College (State Board)
	H.S.C (General Science)
2010	Patwardhan High School (State Board)
	S.S.C (General)
2015	Seed Infotech
	Java Powerpack Course ( java + Struts 2 + SQL )

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Team Leader 2019 - Present Sr. Developer 2017 – 19

# Nyansa

**Convene** – A long term Project where I worked on changing technology of existing application from Flash Based VC solution to WebRTC.

**Languages**: AngularJS, Bootstrap, ViewerJs,

HTML5, CSS3, Spring Boot.

**Database**: MySQL.

Technologies: WebRTC, Websocket, Media

server

AP Automation – Java, Tessaract based Accounts Payable Automation system where OCR based search and identification of given fields from scanned image of payable invoices along with user management and detailed reports was delivered.

**Languages**: Angular 6, Bootstrap, HTML5,

CSS3, Python. **Database**: MySQL.

**Technologies**: Tessaract, Django, Linux

terminal.

**Basic Level Digital Signage** – A quick requirement for screen identification, group based Audio, Video, Text, Image delivery as per rules. Detailed admin panel to schedule content delivery.

Languages: Struts 2, Javascript, Bootstrap.

Database: MySQL.

**Technologies**: Websocket, JMF, Apache POI. **Customized Attendance System** – A unique requirement of attendance system where overtime measurement was required along with user inputs for "Rate" or value % of extra

payment facility.

Languages: ASP. NET, C#.

Database: MySQL.

**Technologies**: Biometric SDK

#### **PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES**

- Bootstrap, Javascript, Jquery
- AngularJS, Angular 8
- Java
- Spring Boot
- Struts 2
- Hibernate
- JPA
- HTML5
- ASP. NET
- SQL
- My SQL
- C, C++ (Basic), C#
- Python (Basic)

#### **TOP SKILLS**

- Bootstrap, Javascript, Jquery
- AngularJS, Angular 8
- Java
- Webrtc
- OCR
- Spring Security, Cloud
- IIS / Tomcat
- Adobe Photoshop
- Edit Plus
- VS Code Studio
- Eclipse

**Land Record Workflow** – A confidential project where time based delivery of transactional workflow system with heavy validations and detailed focus upon UI & UX. Languages: Spring boot, AngularJS Database: MySQL. Technologies: REST API Basic DMS - A web based solution to store and handle soft copy documents along with their metadata. Focused on security to document access. Languages: Struts 2, AngularJS, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3. Database: MySQL Technologies: Apache POI, Web Service. Jr. Software Kavya Software Technologies Developer Hoarding Tracker – A unique requirement of 2016 - 17 hoarding tracker system where overall hoarding bookings was managed along with notification of hoarding expiry time period and detailed reports was delivered Languages: ASP.NET, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3. Database: MySQL. Furniture Inventory - A small software for carpenter to handle workload of making furniture along with employee presently and salary payment records. Mostly focused on UI based on lower typing options for user. Well-structured repots and invoice formats. Languages: ASP.NET, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3. Database: MS SQL

I hereby declare that information shared above is true.

Place: Ratnagiri

Paresh Mestri Date :